# **Pradeep G. Bhosale**

## FRONT-END DEVLOPER

https://pradeepbhosle8.github.io/pradeepbhosle/

90/665, Aijnkya Society, M.H.B. Colony, Dindoshi Nager Malad East, Mumbai -97. +91 9967544174

pradeep.bhosle8@gmail.com

https://github.com/pradeepbhosle8

Creative Front-End Developer offering 4.5+ years of experience providing high-impact web solutions for diverse industry organizations. Skilled in designing, developing and testing multiple web-based applications incorporating a range of technologies. Strong technical skills as a Front-End Developer.

# **KEY SKILLS**

Front-End: Angular 4+, React js, HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, SASS, Gulp, Bootstrap,

JavaScript, Typescript, jQuery, JSON, Ajax. **Back-End:** PHP(basic), Node js, Express.js.

Database: MySQL.

Version Control: Gitlab, Github.

Adobe Creative Suite: Photoshop, Illustrator.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Carnelian Payment Networks India Pvt Ltd.**

Senior Front End Developer

27 September 2021 – Present

Skills & Tools: Angular 12, Primeng, Git-lab, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, Node js Express js restful API.

- M society ( https://paynet.co.in/m-society/ )
  - Determining the structure and design of web pages.
  - Implemented websites, mobile applications, and landing pages from concept through deployment
  - Developing features to enhance the user experience.
  - Ensuring web design is optimized for smart phones.
  - Building, optimizing and maintaining front-end web apps.
- Payment Gateway ( https://paynet.co.in/paynet/ ) Angular 12
  - o Designing and developing user interfaces using angular4+ SPA.

- Adapting interface for modern internet applications using the latest frontend technologies.
- Writing JavaScript, SCSS, and HTML.
- Communicate thoroughly with the back-end department to help build a best-practice RESTful API.

### V'GROW Solutions Pvt Ltd.

Senior Front End Consultant

1<sup>st</sup> January 2020 – 27 September 2021.

Skills & Tools: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, React, Angular4+, Bootstrap, Gitlab.

- Implemented websites, mobile applications, and landing pages from concept through deployment.
- Standardized all output with a new, responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy.
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments.
- Proficiency in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery.
- Coordinating the workflow between the graphic designer, the HTML coder, and yourself

#### FREELANCER

Front End Developer

20 September 2016 – 25 December 2020

Skills & Tools: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap, Materialize, Angular4+, PHP and Git.

- Designed and developed user-friendly website from initial design through completion, optimizing all cross-browser and multi-platform compatibility.
- Translated the requirements and mockups into fully functioning websites using HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript and Angular 4+.
- Responsible for building a new website for the small fleet clients and for the maintenance of the online new platform.
- Designing and Implementing HTML email and websites templates for marketing campaigns, development Clients.
- Built and implemented custom templates for blog in WordPress.

## Craftsvilla.com pvt ltd

Web Designer and Developer

1 September 2015 – 9 September 2016

Skills & Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jquery, WordPress, Angularjs, Git

- Worked with the team, helping them build out their markup and CSS. My specialty is large scale HTML, CSS, focusing on reusability and modularity.
- Creating new Features, Functionality and capabilities on the eCommerce site using Ajax, fetch, JSON and Angular.
- Creating Modular, Responsive landing page using SASS, CSS, HTML and jQuery.
- Fixed bugs from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and speed
- Built and implemented custom templates for Mehndi blog in WordPress.

# **Unotech Software pvt ltd**

Front End Developer, UI Developer

22 July 2013 – 29 August 2015

Skills & Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jquery, JavaScript, Putty, PHP, WordPress

- Developed websites from front to backend using PHP, JavaScript, CSS and HTML.
- Enhanced user experience and accomplish webpage objectives by creating site structure, navigation, page optimization integration.
- Designed and maintained both corporate and client websites, using scripting languages and content management systems including WordPress.
- Client project handle like. Klip.in, BSE scanning doc. Mahindra finance and insurance, PMA, Stepathlon social network, Transpure Pvt ltd etc.

## Robocom pvt ltd

Junior Web Designer, Graphic Designer

18 November 2010 – 4 June 2012

- Developed websites from scratch
- Creating Static site structure, navigation, page optimization, and integration.
- Cooperation with team members Implemented enhancements that improved web functionality and responsiveness.
- Website design, front end development (HTML, CSS, JQuery), logo design, multimedia presentations, designing banners, and other graphic designs.

## **EDUCATION**

**Mumbai University** 

**Diploma in Graphics and Web Designing** 2010

Bachelor of Science in Botany, May 2009